<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Jon Kuperman</title>
		<description>A Blog about Linux Programming and Misinformation...</description>
		<link>http://www.jonkuperman.com</link>
		<atom:link href="http://www.jonkuperman.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Give Google Plus A Chance</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.jonkuperman.com/images/google_plus.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Give Google+ A Chance&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;In The Beginning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Google+ first launched back in 2011 I was definitely on the &lt;em&gt;what a piece of crap&lt;/em&gt; bandwagon. It felt clunky and awkward. Most importantly there was &lt;strong&gt;no one using it&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first joined Facebook it was already happening. Zuckerberg was really smart to introduce the social network to one college at a time. It turned a &quot;lack of users&quot; into &quot;exclusivity&quot; -- genius.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I signed up for a Google+ account right away, clicked around for a few minutes and then never used it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every few months I'd pop back in. Typically it was because I recieved a friend request or wanted to check out a new feature. It had a great looking interface but besides the few Google employees I was following no one was posting updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Google Hangouts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In early 2012 I took a job working remotely for a web development company. Since we were all located in different states, online communication tools were necessary for us to work. We used a lot of different programs for chat but nothing beats Google Hangouts for free video chat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike Skype, there's no software to install, it works on all operating systems and it just has a fun interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still though, besides weekly Google Hangouts I just didn't see much value in Google+ as a social network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Facebook, Going Through Changes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really liked Myspace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I liked everyone having a full profile page, with blog posts and lists of your friends and favorite bands, etc. It made browsing people's profiles a fun activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Facebook first took off it had a similar point to it. It also had tons of cool people on it and a better interface -- It was an easy sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the years Facebook has done all it can to streamline its operation. This isn't so much a criticism, as their 1 billion users speaks to the success of thier operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point is, I really don't enjoy using Facebook as much as I used to. It feels more and more like Twitter to me, filled with endless micro-blog posts and it inspired me to look for something different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Not What I Was Looking For&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking for a new social networking experience, I decided to check back in on Google+ and see how things were progressing. Unfortunatley, there still aren't a ton of people ( that I know ) using the website, and they definitely are no better than Facebook at being anything other than a micro-blogging website -- but man does that interface look inviting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took some time to officially set up my profile. It was really fun. Adding pictures, moving them around and cropping them. It's &lt;strong&gt;so rare&lt;/strong&gt; these days when websites present users with interfaces that are genuinely fun to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I joined a few communities ( groups ) and began chatting. I still have many of my original complaints but at least for now I'm giving it a chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/u/0/102333084042438038555/posts&quot;&gt;find me on Google+&lt;/a&gt; and let's give it a chance!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.jonkuperman.com/give-google-plus-a-chance</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jonkuperman.com/give-google-plus-a-chance</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>An Ode To W3Schools</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;As a young developer, I still distinctly remember the learning process. I remember feeling confused – very confused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every once in a while, I’d have a great victory. But as the old adage goes, the more I learned the less I knew. It was always:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Where do I paste that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s a library?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does a database look like?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Enter W3School – My Personal Savior&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seemed as though no matter what I was stuck on, W3Schools had the answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.jonkuperman.com/images/w3schools.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ode to w3schools&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s really quite incredible. The website covers introductory tutorials on almost every web language. The tutorials are brief, interactive and easy to follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I probably spent more time on w3schools.com than any other website during my first 6 months of web development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;So, Why All The Hatred?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Years have gone by, and I don’t spend so much ( or any ) time on their website anymore. Somewhere along the way, I picked up on the common theme of W3Schools bashing. I think a lot of the mentality can be summed up at the pointedly named W3Fools website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s clear there are a lot of criticisms being made against the website, so let’s just talk about the main three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are inaccuracies on the website, and they won’t fix them.
They appear affiliated with the W3C, which they are not.
They will not wikify their content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Some Stuff Is Wrong And They Won’t Correct It.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is pretty straightforward. I don’t care so much that there are inaccuracies on the website, but if people really have sent in emails and fixes and been ignored that is a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It appears to me that W3Schools is run by a single person. The fact that a small amount of the information is incorrect is really not a big deal when you think about how much content there is. Again though, if he(they) is refusing to fix the problems when they are pointed out, that is too bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;They Appear Affiliated With The W3C&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those in the know the W3C is the World Wide Web Consortium, it is an international organization that governs the web. W3Schools rides off the notoriety of that name despite being unaffiliated. Is that really a complaint? How many JavaScript developers are out there that think this is an issue?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;They Will Not Wikify&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt; While I admire the idea of Wikify’ing websites for the good of the community, it’s a pretty large demand. W3Schools is a wildly successful website ( with a good amount of ads ). It’s a valuable resource to be sure, but that doesn’t mean it should be public property. Again, I’d love to see it happen – but that doesn’t mean it should happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Still A Fan&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; I’ve read a lot of the criticism against the site, but all-in-all I think it’s an amazing resource and we could all appreciate it a bit more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.jonkuperman.com/an-ode-to-w3schools</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jonkuperman.com/an-ode-to-w3schools</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Becoming A Better Programmer – Feels Like Moving Backward</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Last year, I finally turned a spectator’s interest for programming computers into a full time hobby and now it has become a full time job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I continue to learn more about programming, operating systems and development there are a few transitions that I find quite surprising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Nothing Good Has Happened To Computers Since 1993&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you upset yet? Good, because I’m (sort of) kidding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One such strange transition is that I’ve begun using more and more pre-1995 software. When I first began designing websites it seemed that the newer and flashier the software was, the better time I’d have using it to build things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Original Configuration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, my original workstation was something to the extent of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$1,000 Worth Of Hardware&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Windows 7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Full Adobe Suite ( Photoshop &amp;amp; Dreamweaver )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And so on…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Not that this was a particularly bad setup, but it is slow and very costly. As I delve deeper into programming I spend a lot of time worrying about efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This study in efficiency has taken me to some unlikely places. I find time and time again that old UNIX apps make me so much faster than those nice, flashy OSX applications ever did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The New Configuration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days, my set-up looks a little something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The same (used to be) $1,000 Worth Of Hardware&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ubuntu Linux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vim For Text Editing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Terminal Applications Like IRSSI, SSH and FTP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I find these applications exceptional for getting work done quickly. The only thing I find strange is the looming feeling that we don’t have any better tools now than we did 20+ years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.jonkuperman.com/becoming-a-better-programmer-feels-like-moving-backward</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jonkuperman.com/becoming-a-better-programmer-feels-like-moving-backward</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>11 Inches And 300 Bytes – How Fast Is Your Website</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;This semester, I’ve decided to go back to school and finish getting my degree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just to make sure we’re clear, the only reason I’ve decided to finish school is because I’m already more than half way there and it just seems silly to start paying back my loans with nothing to show for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving on…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Apparently Wi-Fi Impedes Learning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, one of my particularly boring classes has some sort of rudimentary technology blocking the campus wireless signal from inside the classrooms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An easy fix right? — Just use my rooted android phone to tether to my laptop. Unfortunately, my class is on the 7th floor and I have somewhere between 0 and 1 bar of 3G service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so I set my phone to tether, and use my Netbook to hop on the tethered Wi-Fi connection. Now I’m sitting in class on an 11″ Netbook screen trying to browse the web at less than 300 bytes per second. This has given me a whole new perspective on designing websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean, really think about it. How fast is your website? How long would it take to load on a 300 bytes per second connection? I know 300 bytes is ridiculous but let’s think about someone on a standard 56k dial-up connection. How long would your website take to load for that person?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.jonkuperman.com/images/how-fast-is-your-website.png&quot; alt=&quot;how fast is your website&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve got my site down to 66.7KB, which is not achievable for anything but a minimalist design like this one. My website would take a little more than a second to load, even on a slow dial-up connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;I’m Awesome, But That’s Not The Point&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real point I’m trying to drive home here is that often times we as designers, developers, publishers or what-have-you get seduced by sweet plugins and forget what the cost is. Remember that each plugin, CSS file, Javascript file, etc is another HTTP request — and they add up quick!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things you probably don’t need that are killing your websites load times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Javascript Comment Systems – Disqus, Livefyre, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More Than One CSS File – Seriously, just combine them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More Than One JavaScript File – See Above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poorly Compressed Images&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not-Minified CSS and JS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Just some food for thought.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.jonkuperman.com/11-inches-and-300-bytes-how-fast-is-your-website</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jonkuperman.com/11-inches-and-300-bytes-how-fast-is-your-website</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Not Another Apple Fan Boy</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.jonkuperman.com/images/macbook.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;not another apple fan boy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried and tried, but today I return my Macbook Pro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About two weeks ago, I had a big client meeting that required a slideshow presentation. I made a great slideshow on my desktop and marked the meeting in my calendar. The day of the meeting I started getting ready and going over my material when it dawned on me, I don’t have a laptop!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long story short — I ended up driving to Best Buy last minute and shopping for laptops.  There are few stores I hate shopping at as much as Best Buy, but that’s where I ended up. I really wanted a laptop that stood out more than the average computer. Something to impress potential clients with and make me feel good about using. It turned out, the laptops I wanted fell somewhere in the $700 range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I really hadn’t considered buying a Macbook at this point, but $700 seemed so close to the $1,300 for a brand new Macbook Pro. When I found out Macbook’s come pre-packaged with iMovie and Garageband I was sold. So I went ahead and bought it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;First Impressions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting my Macbook out of the box was breathtaking. I mean, they really know how to sell you. After taking it out of the box, I really fell for the install process and the user interface. Installing software is really fun and using it is even better. I couldn’t believe the interfaces that most Apple apps came with. I thought I was going to be an Apple user forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main problem I’ve had with the Macbook Pro is performance. I know I bought the cheapest model but seriously there shouldn’t be much a $1,300 notebook can’t do. I tried video editing on it and it lags terribly. Even downloading applications lags out and takes longer than it should. If I spent that much money on a PC it would be lighting fast. I think one day I’ll probably save up and buy a Mac running a quad-core processor. However, for now I’m going to return it and spend my money on something else.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2011 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.jonkuperman.com/not-another-apple-fan-boy</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jonkuperman.com/not-another-apple-fan-boy</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Who Uses Twitter</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.jonkuperman.com/images/twitter.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;who uses twitter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’ve been using Twitter for a while now at &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/insitedesignlab&quot;&gt;@insitedesignlab&lt;/a&gt; for my work and I think I’m finally getting the hang of it. It’s obvious to me that it is a great marketing and education tool but I can’t help but wonder how to use it as a form of social media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How I Use Twitter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been on Twitter for about 6 months now and I’ve gone through a few different strategies for getting the most out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first I tried using Twitter as though it were some streaming RSS Feed. I only subscribed to my favorite blogs and kept an eye out for updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This worked quite well at first. I’d check in and see what new posts were circulating the internet in my field, reading them as I went. But after a while it started to feel lonely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I tried making friends on Twitter. I followed some advice I had seen on a few blogs and waiting for people I followed to ask questions, jumping in to answer them. I did this about 10 times and two things happened:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No one ever wrote me back&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;None of them ever followed me&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now, I understand that most of the people I follow are famous and have thousands of followers themselves but it was certainly discouraging to not get a single response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Real Problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking back on the issue, I’m fairly sure the real problem is that I don’t have any of my real friends on Twitter. It seems to me that Twitter is a great tool and your followers easily grow from somewhat of a snowball effect. My issue, being that I don’ t have the initial amount of snow necessary to start the snowball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re The Solution!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wanna help my problem and get your Twitter account going as well? &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/insitedesignlab&quot;&gt;Add me on Twitter and let’s start talking!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m really looking to meet some people that are interested in web development and maybe collaborate on some awesome projects!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.jonkuperman.com/who-uses-twitter</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jonkuperman.com/who-uses-twitter</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Goodbye NASCAR, Hello Android Freedom</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.jonkuperman.com/images/root2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;goodbye nascar, hello android freedom&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I finally Rooted my Evo 4g.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I got an HTC Evo 4g something like 8 months ago and honestly thought I was going to try rooting it as soon as I got it home. I’ve been a huge Linux nerd for years and the thought of having root on an open source cell phone was almost too much for me to handle. And then I had three realizations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s a $600 phone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don’t know anything about phone operating systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When my Linux computer breaks (as they always do) and I have to spend the afternoon puttering around with it, that’s annoying. If my cell phone broke for a day or two that would be catastrophic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, I put the plan on hold for a while and just made the most of the EVO’s fairly awesome stock interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Push&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, about a month ago, my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.larrykuperman.com/&quot;&gt;dad&lt;/a&gt; went and rooted his Samsung Epic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, as a software developer in my twenties, it’s not easy accepting that your father is a better hacker than you. But there you have it. He rooted his phone and was happily playing with all the happy features that come along with new found freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Outcome&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jealousy got the best of me, and we got together yesterday and did a root plus &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyanogenmod.com/&quot;&gt;cyanogenmod&lt;/a&gt; rom install on my EVO. See the pictures above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to say after all the hype I’ve heard about cyanogenmod, I wasn’t super impressed with the out-of-the-box OS. It felt minimal and the UI wasn’t nearly as impressive as I had hoped. So far, the applications that have helped me achieve the look and performance I was looking for have been:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AdFree&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced Task Killer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dialer One&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Launcher Pro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sense Analog Clock&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;And the tools that made the whole thing possible:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3wjhWSalETs&amp;feature=results_main&amp;playnext=1&amp;list=PL28A547E5FC04C8F3&quot;&gt;This Youtube Video On How To Get Root With Android 2.3.3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ROM Manager&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Titanium Backup PRO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I thought about linking all those apps, but it’s probably just as easy for you to type them into your phone manually. Definitely check ‘em out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I’m loving the cool new look, improved performance and complete lack of crappy Sprint endorsed bloatware. Goodbye Sprint News, NASCAR, Blockbuster app. Hello Android Freedom!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2011 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.jonkuperman.com/goodbye-nascar-hello-android-freedom</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jonkuperman.com/goodbye-nascar-hello-android-freedom</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>What Is Technorati</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.jonkuperman.com/images/technorati.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;what is technorati&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technorati serves a few purposes, I’m just not clear on what it does for publishers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*hidden motive, I have to post this Technorati code, Q779M4W4TU7H  , in a post to claim this blog. I though I might as well use it to write a full fledged blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Why Technorati Is Awesome&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it’s totally great to have a master list of all existing blogs. I think it’s awesome to keep statistics on the state of the blogosphere and Technorati does it well. I even think it’s great to give blogs numerical rankings and highlight blogs that are quickly on the rise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Where I’m Confused&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I don’t understand is what the benefit is for claiming your blog as a publisher. Will having your blog claimed get you more traffic or better your blog in any way? I don’t think it does and I don’t see a reason to claim my blogs. Yet I’m also not famous or super successful so I’ll continue to follow the trend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2011 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.jonkuperman.com/what-is-technorati</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jonkuperman.com/what-is-technorati</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Responsive Web Design</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.jonkuperman.com/images/RWD-feature.png&quot; alt=&quot;Responsive Web Design&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've been thinking a lot lately about responsive web design. It was most of the inspiration behind me building this site. This book by Ethan Marcotte has been my driving force lately but I don't want to get ahead of myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What Is Responsive Web Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common misconception is that responsive web design and fluid width websites are the same thing. The big difference is that responsive web design uses &lt;strong&gt;CSS3 Media Queries&lt;/strong&gt; to re-style elements based on screen size. This means that elements don't just shrink and grow, they adapt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the most common use of responsive web design is using media queries to toss an element ( usually a sidebar ) down below the main content area. This allows the important information, like the content, to fill up smaller screens while less important data in the sidebar can be shuffled down below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Why It Matters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Responsive Design is particularly important in this day an age because of how many different devices we have browsing the internet.  Are your users going to be viewing your website on a phone? a tablet? a laptop or desktop? With screen sizes ranging from 300px wide to over 1900px, shouldn't you have a website that accommodates it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a fixed width, non-responsive website you are guaranteeing a sub-par experience for at least some of your visitors. For example, if you make a standard 960px wide website, you giving a horizontal scroll to anyone with a smaller screen ( including people using Windows 7's new half-sized window feature ), and at the same time your website will look tiny to anyone with a 1900+ pixel monitor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Information Architecture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I'm really not sure what &lt;em&gt;Information Architecture&lt;/em&gt; means but I've decided to go ahead and use it anyway. One important part of responsive design is deciding what information should be highlighted if some has to be shuffled below. If you're using media queries to shuffle elements of your website, which ones &lt;em&gt;deserve&lt;/em&gt; to stay up at the top?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Where To Go From Here&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you're looking to get into responsive design, you should check out the following resources:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://css-tricks.com/&quot;&gt;CSS Tricks - A great blog and a great example of responsive design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abookapart.com/products/responsive-web-design&quot;&gt;Reponsive Web Design - A Book Apart's awesome book on responsive design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://designmodo.com/responsive-design-examples/&quot;&gt;Design Modo - An amazing visual round-up of responsive design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2011 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.jonkuperman.com/responsive-web-design</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jonkuperman.com/responsive-web-design</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Photoshop Is In My Way</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.jonkuperman.com/images/adobe.png&quot; alt=&quot;Photoshop is in my way&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;I Am Not A Graphic Designer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I start this rant, I think it's only fair to tell you all that I am in no way a graphic designer. I love design, both print and web but I've never been good at creation.  This attack is not actually at Adobe Photoshop, which is obviously a great piece of software, but it is the now standard practice of web designers using Photoshop to create mock-ups and drafts before building their website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My problem is simply that Photoshop is not the medium in which websites exist. Websites exist in web browsers and should be designed accordingly. Photoshop is often times an unnecessary step between your vision and an amazing website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;I Am A Web Designer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I'm not a big print designer, I do make websites for a living. I'm not just blowing steam here and I really do think you can efficiently run a web design business without making Photoshop mock-ups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm not saying you should just jump in to a WordPress install and hope for the best. I believe in sketching, wire frames and information architecture. However, I think that all of these things can be done easily and more efficiently with pen and paper.  After sketching everything out, why waste your time making a function-less picture? Just go ahead and code your design. If your client wants something changed, go for it! Just don't make your job harder than it has to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;37 Signals Agrees With Me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This really isn't meant as social proof or anything. I was just fully prepared to take this stance alone when I found this article:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/1061-why-we-skip-photoshop&quot;&gt;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/1061-why-we-skip-photoshop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2011 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.jonkuperman.com/photoshop-is-in-my-way</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jonkuperman.com/photoshop-is-in-my-way</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>